[Snake] Stop.
[Wolf] I'll stop if you just
explain it to me, because I don't…
[Snake] Would you please
just drop it?
[Wolf] All right, all right.
Fine, fine, fine.
Consider it dropped.
It's dropped. It's on the ground.
Good.
But, I mean, come on,
everybody loves birthdays.
[groans]
You got decorations,
you got balloons,
you got parties and cake.
Look. I don't need presents,
I don't want decorations,
and I'm not a cake guy.
Seriously, though,
you don't like cake?
Name one food
better than cake.
Guinea pig.
Again, with the guinea pig.
[chuckles]
I bet if I blindfolded you,
you wouldn't be able to tell
the difference between
a skunk and a guinea pig.
Wrong.
Snakes have impeccable taste buds.
I can taste air.
-Air?
-Yes. Air.
[lapping] Mmm.
Nice.
I don't know.
They're a little, uh…
They're a little cute
for my taste.
That's what makes them
so delicious.
You're not just eating food,
you're eating pure goodness.
It's not about the pig.
It's about what it symbolizes
on a deeper level.
So, you can…
You can taste air?
-Ah. Forget about it.
-What else you got?
Wait, wait, wait.
Can you also hear color?
-[laughing]
-All right, all right.
-Can you see sound?
-Okay.
'Cause we should really be
capitalizing on these skills.
Okay, all right, fine.
-Get it all out. Get it all out now.
-Okay, okay.
[gags]
Look at that. 4:00 p.m.
Now I know the exact moment
our friendship died.
[laughs]
-Let's bounce.
-Yep.
Tastes like, uh, you're gonna
stick me with the bill… again.
-Well, it is my birthday.
-[patrons gasp, shudder]
So, now you play the birthday card?
That's interesting.
[laughs]
Can we get a check, please,
when you get a chance?
Hello?
Checkity-check-check.
You know what?
We're just gonna leave
the money right here, okay?
You know the one good thing
about this place?
-What?
-We never have to wait for a table.
Well, isn't that every place?
Hey, man. How you been?
I haven't seen you…
-Snake attack! [laughs]
-[patrons gasping]
Oh! Mints.
Sorry, folks.
I'm switching him to decaf.
[laughs]
-All right.
-[both] Let's do this.
-[pedestrians screaming]
-[tires screeching]
-[screaming continues]
-[crashing]
Guinea pig, huh?
It's the Rolls Royce of rodents.
Yeah, but it's still a rodent.
You know what I mean?
Don't mind us,
just robbin' this place.
[people screaming]
-[glass shattering]
-[alarm blaring]
[tires squealing]
-Whoo! Yeah! Go bad…
-Or go home.
[both laughing]
[engine revs]
Hey, you. Get over here.
Little bit closer.
Oh, I know what it is.
You're afraid.
Because I'm the big, bad wolf.
Well, I'm not surprised.
I am the villain in every story.
-Isn't that right, Mr. Snake?
-[laughs] Yep.
Say hello to Mr. Snake.
Serpentine, safecrackin' machine.
Imagine Houdini, but with no arms.
Kinda guy who'd tell ya the glass
is half empty, then steal it from ya.
He's also my best bud,
and today's his birthday!
Not relevant.
He's a sweetheart.
You're a sweetheart.
[siren wailing]
Well, look who's here.
Took 'em long enough.
Watch this.
Three… Two…
One.
And over here is Ms. Tarantula.
Our in-house hacker,
pocket search engine,
our traveling tech wizard.
We call her "Webs."
-[siren blaring]
-[horns honking]
Very slick, Webs.
I also took over the police dispatch,
blurred their
satellite imaging system,
grounded their chopper,
and one more thing…
You didn't.
I got a special delivery for…
[screams] Whoa, don't eat me!
Please, don't eat me!
Happy birthday,
Mr. Grumpypants.
I think I hate you.
-Ooh!
-Oh!
Guys! It's me!
I was the construction worker!
[Wolf] And this is Mr. Shark,
master of disguise.
Apex predator of a thousand faces.
His greatest trick?
Stealing the Mona Lisa,
disguised as the Mona Lisa.
Dig that.
Watch it, big tuna.
I'm tryin' to work here.
Keep it cool, baby.
Birthdays should be chill.
[Wolf] And rounding out the crew…
[knocking]
Surprise! [cackling]
[Wolf] …is Mr. Piranha.
-He's a loose cannon…
-[thugs laughing]
…with a short fuse, willing to scrap
with anyone or anything.
He's brave.
-He's fearless.
-[thugs screaming]
Uh, who am I kidding? He's crazy.
[laughing, speaking Spanish]
Uh, Piranha,
did we forget something?
-What?
-The present. You know?
Oh, um, of course I didn't forget.
[siren wailing continues]
You know you fart
when you lie, right?
What? No, I fart when I'm nervous.
-Yeah. Nervous about lying.
-[stomach gurgling]
I'm sorry.
-[farts]
-[Tarantula] Piranha!
Don't breathe it in.
I breathed it in!
[Wolf, Snake gasp]
[Wolf] Yeah, they're a bit eccentric,
but when you're born us,
you don't exactly win
many popularity contests.
Shark!
-[beachgoer] A shark!
-[screaming]
Do I wish people
didn't see us as monsters?
Eight legs, eight times the cardio!
-Spider!
-[Wolf] Sure, I do.
What's up, papa?
But these are the cards we've been
dealt, so we might as well play them.
-[lock clicks]
-Jackpot!
Yes!
[tires screeching]
Um…
-What the thorax?
-Are you crazy?
What? I just wanted
a longer car chase.
It's the best part.
[police radio chatter]
Chief! It's…
Them.
[grunts]
Webs, hit it.
["Stop, Drop, Roll" plays on radio]
Get them!
-[all laughing]
-[engine revs]
-[officers clamoring]
-[sirens wailing]
♪ Hooked on hip-hop phonics
Yeah it works for me ♪
♪ So jump aboard
Yeah, this train is free ♪
♪ The conductor let me
Toot my whistle ♪
♪ The instructor
Of the funky uncle fizzle ♪
♪ We be dancing on a lake
When it ain't froze over ♪
♪ We be walking on water
While you're sinking your rover ♪
♪ If you step any close
You'll be eatin' some teeth ♪
[cackling]
I'm gonna put you guys away
for so long,
your fleas will have fleas!
[Chief grunts]
[all gasp]
Chief! You want some cake?
-You seem a little hangry.
-[all laughing]
Get that thing
out of my face before I…
-Excuse me, Chief.
-What?
[siren wailing continues]
You're mine.
[engine revs]
Hermano!
[tires squealing]
[Wolf] Whoo!
[all screaming]
Yeah. We may be bad,
but we're so good at it.
[all laughing]
No, no, no, no, no!
No, no! Keep runnin', Wolf.
One of these days
your luck is gonna run out.
[elevator bell dings]
All right, Piranha. You're up.
[vocalizing]
Happy birth…
-[gasps]
-Seriously?
Snake, come on.
At least make a toast.
-Toast.
-Come on.
-Okay, all right, a toast.
-Yeah!
Fine.
I've made a lot of enemies
in my time.
I mean, a lot!
But out of all the people
in the world,
I hate you guys the least.
That was actually
kind of beautiful.
You a poet, man.
To Mr. Snake
and his strange dislike of birthdays.
[all cheering]
Everyone say, "Robbery!"
[all] Robbery!
Look at those dimples.
Happy birthday, buddy.
Okay. Now, dig in, fellas.
Yes! [laughs]
-No, no, no!
-Piranha!
-[Wolf] Don't do that.
-[Tarantula] That was so gross.
[Shark] That was my lunch.
-[Piranha] You snooze, you lose.
-[Tarantula laughing]
[Wolf] You like that.
Nice.
-Ooh! Wow!
-[Snake gasps]
I forgot we had those Push Pops.
Man, my tummy is rumblin'
like a kraken right now.
Yeah. Want it?
You know he's not
gonna give it to you.
No. I believe that, deep down,
Snake is a kind and generous soul.
Why?
Here. Take it.
Oh, yeah! Pop me, please.
[gasps, sighs]
-[laughs] Sucker.
-Come on, man!
Now you're gonna make me
get all aggressive.
-Animals.
-Spit it out! Spit it out!
[Snake] Never!
Let's see
what they're sayin' about us today.
What up? It's Tiffany Fluffit,
Channel 6 Action News.
The Bad Guys have struck again…
-Guys, stop it. We're on TV.
-…with their most brazen heist yet,
proving once more that they are
the most diabolical criminals
of our time.
"Diabolical." That's new.
Know what it sounds like? A cologne.
"Diabolical."
To address this heinous crime spree
is the newly elected governor,
Diane Foxington.
-Governor?
-[Diane] Okay, yeah.
I hear you. I hear you.
Listen, listen.
We all know
how dastardly the Bad Guys are.
You bet we are.
But more than anything…
[chuckles]
…I feel sorry for them.
What?
These so-called "Bad Guys" are
really just second-rate has-beens.
Behind their amateurish antics
and, frankly, unoriginal capers…
I mean, really? Another bank?
…is nothing but a deep well of anger.
I ain't angry! You're angry!
-Denial.
-Not true.
And self-loathing.
The only one I self-loathe is you.
And those are holes that no amount of
cash or priceless art can ever fill.
What's on the Food Network?
Can we just forget about
the Bad Guys…
Who is she to judge us?
-…and focus on more positive things?
-[growls]
And what could be more positive than
the Annual Good Samaritan Awards,
where tomorrow night I will present
the Golden Dolphin
to this year's goodest citizen.
-I can't believe I voted for her.
-You voted for her?
[Tarantula]
What? She's good on climate change.
Wait. What's going on?
You've got that twinkle in your eye.
Guys, who's up for another job?
A big one.
[all gasp]
The Golden Dolphin.
Seriously?
Oh! I thought I was
the crazy one.
That job has broken every criminal
who's tried it.
The Bucharest Bandits. Lucky Jim.
The Crimson Paw.
Actually, the Crimson Paw
was never arrested.
Yeah, but he never stole
anything again.
Snake, what better way
to wipe that smirk off
the governor's fuzzy face,
than stealin' the Golden Dolphin
from right under her whiskers?
This is the holy grail of thievery.
If we pull this off,
we'll cement our legacy as
the greatest criminals of all time.
Whoa, whoa, buddy.
I thought we weren't supposed to
make things personal.
Besides, we've got
a good thing goin' here.
Friends, freedom,
and just look at this loot!
All right, you're right. Forget it.
The Dolphin job is off.
Good.
I guess the pig
will get his trophy after all.
Yeah, I guess he would…
What do you mean, "pig"?
Yes, did I not mention that?
That's weird.
I thought I mentioned that it was…
The Good Samaritan is…
A guinea pig?
[shuddering]
What do you say, Snakey?
Better than cake.
[laughing]
[grunts] Okay. Fine.
But he better be delicious.
[laughs] Are we all in this together?
[Wolf] So, here's the plan.
Like every year, the ceremony will be
held at the Museum of Fine Arts,
where the Golden Dolphin
will be positioned
just beyond the backstage curtain.
Sounds easy.
Sounds easy, hermano.
But to get there, we'll need to
bypass three levels of security.
So, step one.
We'll need to blend in.
♪ Baby, I'm howlin' for you ♪
[Wolf] Professor Marmalade,
this year's recipient
of the Golden Dolphin,
the most annoying
good creature on the planet.
Professor, in the past year,
you've stopped wars, fed the hungry
and saved countless pandas.
Some have described your goodness
as second only to Mother Teresa.
Oh, Tiffany.
It's not a competition.
And if it were,
it would really be more of a tie.
But we can all agree
that there is a flower of goodness
inside all of us
just waiting to blossom.
[Wolf] Once inside,
there are two armored doors.
The first can only be opened
by a special key card
that is carried by our dear friend,
the chief of police.
The second is outfitted
with a retinal scanner
and guarded by
an elite special-ops unit
trained to strike first
and ask questions later.
[insect buzzing]
[Wolf]
Governor Foxington is the only one
who has clearance
to open the second door.
So, step two, she and I will need to
get up close and personal.
Enjoy your evening, Mr. Ambassador.
[Wolf] Interesting piece.
Trashy, pointless and pretentious.
Hmm. They say that art reveals
more about the viewer
than the artist.
Mister…
-Poodleton. Oliver Poodleton.
-Okay.
It's about time someone stood up
to those diabolical Bad Guys.
Though, I've got to say,
no one's succeeded yet.
Eh. I don't think it'll be that hard.
I have a feeling
it'll be harder than you think.
I'd say they're one epic job away
from cementing their legacy.
Mr. Poodleton. You're funny.
I am?
The only legacy they're cementing
is life in prison.
Did you see their last job?
Ugh, unsecured exits,
crude disguises,
compulsive showboating.
I mean, it was a mess.
All the classic signs
of a crew in decline.
Next, they're gonna make it personal.
That's when you know they're toast.
Uh, well, that's your opinion.
It is. And I'm the governor.
As for the sculpture,
I think it's about perspective.
If you look closely enough,
even trash can be recycled
into something beautiful.
[Wolf] How about that.
I guess some things
aren't always as they appear.
That reminds me, may I?
I can't miss a photo op with
the governor and a pile of garbage.
Mr. Poodleton,
you're too hard on yourself.
Hey…
[guests chattering]
Okay, friends.
It's showtime.
[Wolf] Once we're in,
it's on to step three.
We split up
and we take our positions.
Officers, if the Bad Guys
crash this event,
I am definitely going to lose my job.
And I will not hesitate to
take you down with me.
Now, move out!
[officers] Yes, ma'am!
Hut, hut, hut, hut!
Hut, hut, hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut, hut, hut, hut!
Mic's on.
Everyone on comms, do you copy?
-Copy.
[Snake laughing]
A drink for the pretty lady?
No, thank you.
My life is too complicated right now.
Uh…
[groans, gags]
Boys, it's dolphin season.
[muffled mumbling]
Copy that. I'm on the move.
Unit Two,
is the backstage area still secure?
[officer] Unit Two. All clear.
This is where
all the training pays off.
-[grunts, groans]
-Pardon me. Terribly sorry.
Not a problem, sir.
Keep your eyes open, boys.
They could be anywhere,
just waiting to humiliate us.
[Wolf laughs]
Wolf is in position.
Piranha,
you all penguin-suited and booted?
Affirmative. I'm a clean, mean
dolphin-stealin' machine.
What's goin' on, guys?
[guests chattering]
-[screams]
-[Wolf grunting]
[old lady panting]
[sighs] Here, let me help you.
Are you okay, ma'am?
[panting] My gracious, yes.
I may be dizzy, but I'm alive!
Thanks to you.
What are you…
Oh. [moans]
[groans]
Thank you, dear.
You're such a good boy.
[grunts]
All good, brother?
Yeah, all good. Yeah, yeah.
Um… [babbling]
Webs, what do you say
about movin' on to step four?
Copy that. Shark, you're up.
Do your thing.
-Do I get to improvise?
-Yes, fine.
Improvise. But please be subtle.
I'm having a baby!
Is there a doctor?
Or perhaps several security guards
that could leave their post
and help me?
-[gasps]
-[elevator bell dings]
[people clamoring]
"Fish surprise"?
Surprise!
-[shouts]
-[security guards grunting]
[Wolf] Hey, Webs,
can you enhance this…
[Tarantula] Done.
Eight steps ahead of you, Wolfie.
-Ah.
-[announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
your MC for
the Good Samaritan Awards…
[huffing]
[Wolf] All right, Shark, we're in.
Oops, I forgot. I'm not pregnant.
[announcer]
…president of the committee,
Governor Diane Foxington.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Last year, we faced our biggest test
when a meteorite crashed
into our dear city.
That meteorite didn't just make
a hole in our city,
it made a hole in our hearts.
[guests] Aw.
But even in tragedy,
Professor Marmalade,
he did what he does so well.
He made us
look at things differently.
And thanks to you, Marmalade,
the Love Crater Meteorite
will forever serve
as a symbol of how there is good,
even in the worst places.
[guests applauding]
Whoo!
[Piranha laughs, grunts]
Hurry up.
And successfully reversed
climate change
for the well-being of all of us.
This is going surprisingly smoothly.
What the molt is that?
The Wolf-Piranha-Snake-Shark-
Tarantula Protection System.
-[Tarantula] The W.P.S.S.T.?
-This was not supposed to happen.
-What?
-Guys, calm down. I'm on it.
Initiating
W.P.S.S.T. Override Protocol.
Get it, queen!
-[Wolf] Did it work?
-Just give me five minutes.
[Diane] And now,
please join me in welcoming
to the stage…
We don't have five minutes.
…Professor Marmalade!
-Oh.
-[guests cheering]
We love you,
Professor Marmalade!
The pig is on the move.
I repeat, the pig is on the move.
[Wolf] Webs, Webs!
-The curtain's going up any minute!
-It's not letting me in.
Check your system preferences.
You probably need to
download a driver.
Try rebooting.
Oh, my gosh, you fixed it.
-[Wolf, Snake] Really?
-No!
[Chief] Hey, Larry.
Come on, open up.
What did we say about lockin' doors?
No, no, no.
Shark, I got a situation here.
[Shark] Copy that. I'm on my way.
[stomach gurgling]
Hurry up, guys.
Time to turn this baby on beast mode.
Eat it, W.P.S.S.T.
-[gurgling continues]
-Please, not now.
-[Piranha] Wolf!
-Wait, wait, wait. No, Piranha!
-This award is for…
-[farts]
[clears throat] As I was saying…
No, no, no.
[sniffs]
Piranha! Are you kidding me?
[Piranha] Sorry!
And that's why
my Gala for Goodness
will raise all the money needed
for those less fortunate.
-[Chief] Come on!
-[knocking]
[gasps]
I'm starting to get mad here, Larry.
[Wolf] Webs! Webs!
And now, the moment
we've all been waiting for.
-[Wolf gasps]
-Whoa!
[Shark] Excuse me.
Is this the ladies' room?
Oh, uh, you need to take a right
at the end of the hall, ma'am.
[gasps] Whoa.
Yes! Whoop-bam!
Oh, come on!
And now, it is my honor to award
Professor Marmalade
with the Golden Dolphin!
[guests murmuring]
-No!
Yes! I mean, yes!
What?
[screams]
Everyone, everyone,
please don't panic.
-[guests murmuring]
-Just stay calm.
I'm sure
there's an explanation for this.
I repeat, please do not panic.
[Wolf] Nice work, everybody.
Now, let's make like a wolf
and get the pack outta here.
Ah, wordplay.
I don't get it.
[Marmalade]
Diane, Diane, if I may…
You have to understand,
I didn't bring hope back to the city
for an award.
I did these good things
because of how they made me feel.
That tingly feeling I get.
That shiver up my spine.
The wag in my tiny tail.
Because you see,
being good just feels so good.
And when you're good, you're loved.
-Huh?
-Wolf?
-What are you doing?
-[Tarantula] Go!
-[Shark] Go!
It's the Bad Guys!
Arrest them!
Hut, hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut, hut, hut!
They stole the Golden Dolphin!
Come on, you can't prove that.
[metal clanking]
My baby!
On your knees, Bad Guys,
with your hands up!
Never! We're outta here.
So long, suckers!
Well, this just got a little weird.
[siren wailing]
[Tiffany Fluffit]
The Bad Guys go bust!
The nefarious fivesome
has finally been captured.
And I, Tiffany Fluffit,
am first on the scene.
Wow. You know, I just realized
that I have devoted my entire
adult life to putting you in jail.
You are my purpose.
Without you, who am I?
I'm just kiddin'!
This is the best moment of my life!
It's the end of the Bad Guys.
No!
Get your hands off of me.
You're begging for
a bitin' right now.
Wolf!
[reporter] Professor Marmalade!
Madam Governor!
Professor Marmalade!
-Madam Governor! Madam Governor!
-One at a time. One at a time.
-Hey. Hey!
-Excuse me.
-[reporters gasp]
-Sorry to interrupt,
I just wanted to congratulate
the governor here.
I gotta say,
you really got us pegged.
We're just a deep well
of anger and self-loathing.
-Denial.
-[Wolf] Sure. That too.
-Narcissism.
-[Wolf] Yeah. Yeah.
Emotional emptiness.
So, we're on the same page.
What is he doin'?
Sadly, we were never given a chance
to be anything more
than second-rate criminals.
If only there was someone
who could help the flower of goodness
inside us blossom.
Some icon of love
and forgiveness, like…
I don't know, Mother Teresa.
Best thing is
to just throw us in jail
for the rest of our hopeless lives.
Yeah, that's the plan.
Wait, wait! No, no!
-Get in there.
-Ow!
-[Marmalade] Wait!
-[people murmuring]
B-Beg pardon?
Mr. Wolf may be a savage beast.
Basically, walking garbage.
Sorry, I'm making a point.
Do what you need to do, pal.
But how can we say they're hopeless
if they've never been given a chance?
What if…
What if we tried
a little experiment, Diane?
As you know,
my Gala for Goodness…
the #Charity Event of the Year
is coming up.
If I can prove to everyone at that
gala that the Bad Guys have changed,
will you set them free
and give them a clean start?
[people gasping]
What? Professor Marmalade!
No, no, no.
Don't you see what he's doing?
He's playing you!
But it was my idea.
It was his idea.
But only because
you made him have it!
Madam Governor,
you can't just let them go.
Professor, I'm not about to put
the safety of the city on the line
for an experiment.
Excuse me, Madam Governor.
I seem to remember that
a wise person once said,
"Even trash can be recycled
into something beautiful."
[scoffs]
Okay. I'm game.
But only because it's you, Professor.
No!
We'll hold onto the dolphin
until the gala,
just to remove
any unnecessary temptation.
Of course. Good thinking.
That's why you're governor.
Now that everyone's happy…
Not happy.
…I, Rupert Marmalade the Fourth,
will turn the Bad Guys into
the Good Guys!
[all] Ooh!
I think these belong to you.
Hey!
[Diane] Not everyone
gets a second chance.
Make the most of it, Mr. Poodleton.
[sirens wailing]
[Snake] Wolf.
What are you doing?
-[Wolf] What?
-Yeah.
Oh, that!
I'm sorry, I thought it was obvious.
We're gonna go good.
Uh, you totally lost me.
I told him to stop drinkin'
out of the toilet.
Hey, did you get hit on the head?
What? No, I didn't get…
My cousin got hit on the head
with an anchor,
and after that,
he only swam in a circle.
No, guy, guys, guys.
You're not following me.
We're gonna pretend to go good.
Just a few days with Marmalade.
And then,
we roll into the gala as good guys
and roll out scot-free with…
[all] The Golden Dolphin!
You got it.
Since when do we not finish a job?
The Bad Guys become the Good Guys
so we can stay the bad guys.
-You know what I'm saying?
-[all laughing]
Bad guys acting good?
It's the ultimate bad-guy thing.
It's fantastic.
Wolf, you're a genius!
It's gonna be, like,
the most relaxing con ever.
Like a vacation.
Oh, oh-oh-oh! A con-cation.
-[all laughing]
-[siren wailing continues]
[Shark]
My parents met on a con-cation!
[seagulls squawking]
[Marmalade humming]
[doorbell rings]
Oh, goody!
[Wolf] Wow!
[Tarantula] Big and fancy.
Rodent's got taste. Okay!
Almost makes me wanna be cute.
[Marmalade] They say experience
is the best teacher.
And they are wrong.
I am.
Good morning,
students of goodness.
And welcome to the first day
of the rest of your best life.
A giant butt!
Huh?
Uh, it's-- it's not a butt.
It's a lamp in the shape
of the Love Crater Meteorite,
my greatest…
I wonder whose butt it is.
-[Wolf gasps]
-Uh…
Once again,
it's not a butt, thank you.
It's a heart.
-Now, as I was saying…
-Then why does it have cheeks?
-Shut it!
-What?
I've never seen a heart
with cheeks.
-[chuckles] It's not a…
-Booty!
It's not a butt! Not a butt!
Does he know what a butt is?
[grunts] As I was saying,
on the outside,
the five of you are villains,
predators,
remorseless sociopaths.
Oh, stop,
you're makin' me blush.
But inside, there's a flower.
The flower of goodness.
And when it blooms
and you feel that tingle
of positivity
radiating through your body,
you're going to want to feel it
all the time.
So, we're going for a tingle?
Not any tingle.
The tingle of goodness.
Which you'll feel in my
state-of-the-art Sharing Laboratory!
Okay, Mr. Snake,
I'm going to give you a Push Pop.
Great! Push Pop just for me!
No, to share.
Why?
Well, on a fundamental level,
it's about putting someone else's
needs ahead of your own.
[chuckling]
Oh, no. No way.
Snake…
[sighs] All right, all right.
This is gonna taste extra sweet,
'cause I know how bad you want it.
[groaning]
Pop me, please. Ah!
Nope!
-Sucker!
-That's it! I'll teach you to share!
[all gasp]
I like sharin'. It's yummy. Mmm.
[Snake] Totally worth it.
Well, that's terrifying.
Let's try something simpler.
A good person always pays attention
to the needs of others.
Now, here's a kindly, frail grandma.
[all laughing]
Mr. Piranha,
help Grandma across the street.
Pish! Sure, sure, sure.
I do this all the time.
Here you go, ma'am.
[laughing]
Oh, he is totally gonna blow it.
-What was that? What did you say?
-[Tarantula laughing]
-You think I can't do this?
-No, no, no, Piranha…
[horn honking]
[Wolf screaming, grunts]
Maybe simpler?
[cat meowing]
Hey, look!
It's a cat stuck in a tree.
It doesn't get
much simpler than that.
Now, what in this scenario
would give you that good tingle?
Eating it? This is why I always carry
two pieces of bread with me.
No. I want you to s…
-Smack it.
-Skin it?
Stab it.
-Sauté it.
-Sing to it?
Save it. I want you to save…
It's so obvious…
I want you to save it.
[all] Oh! Right, right.
[all] Here, kitty, kitty cat!
[cat meowing]
Whoa,
that cat is obviously defective.
What is wrong with you?
You're gonna give it a heart attack.
I'll handle this.
What's up, papa!
[yowling]
Get him off my face!
He's on my face!
No, no, no! Listen.
What are you doing?
[Wolf groaning]
Okay. What, may I ask,
are you good at?
-Stealing stuff?
-Oh, yeah, we're great at that.
-Robbery.
-Larceny.
-Wire fraud.
-Extortion.
-Tax evasion.
-Heists.
-[Tarantula] Mail fraud.
-Wait. "Heists," you say?
Well, that's…
Yeah, that's kind of our specialty.
I might just have an idea.
[protestors]
Free the pigs! Free the pigs!
That is an animal testing lab.
Within, 200,000 helpless guinea pigs,
all being poked and prodded
by sadistic scientists.
Guinea pigs, you say?
Snake…
I want you to rescue them.
But this is a heist for good.
So, I brought something
more friendly for you to wear.
Bye.
Well, there goes our street cred.
At least it's comfy.
[Wolf] All right,
we need to distract that scientist.
-Shark, you're up.
-Copy that.
Okay. We're gonna need
a rope and a hook.
I got this one.
-What?
-You're volunteering?
You've never volunteered
for anything.
Sure I did. Right now.
-Throw me up there! Giddy up!
-Really?
Yep.
I'm 99% sure you can make it.
-Okay.
-Let's do it!
-Hey there, son.
-Dad?
I know you've got an important job,
but I hope you still have time
for a catch with your old man.
-[gasps]
-[Snake groans]
-Hey, kiddo.
-[Snake] 96% sure.
You'll always be my special boy.
[groans] Maybe 90%.
I've been waiting my entire life
for this moment.
-Okay, then. Now, go long.
-[Snake] Ow! I don't know.
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy!
Thank you, Daddy!
[laughing]
Ow! Fifty? What day is it?
[Snake] Who am I?
Right. The guinea pigs are locked
behind a three-foot thick steel door.
The only way in
is through the vents.
I got it.
Upsy-daisy!
♪ Over the filters
And through the vents… ♪
I have never seen him so chipper.
Has he been meditating?
♪ To Guinea Pig Land we… ♪
[Snake screams]
-[squeaking]
-[groans]
[slurping]
Oh.
[whispering] Snake attack.
[protestors chanting]
Hey, look! It's Professor Marmalade.
Yes, that's right.
It's me. Help has arrived.
Just keep your eyes
glued to that door.
Snake. Come on, Snake, open up.
Relax. These doors are complicated.
-[Tarantula] Are you kidding me?
-[guinea pigs squealing]
What do you think you're doing?
We're supposed to save them,
not eat them.
Well, I'd say
they've gone to a better place.
[burps, laughs]
That's it.
Spit them out!
We're gonna save you
whether you like it or not.
We're saving you, stupid hair balls.
Not that door. The other door.
Hey, hey!
Any second.
[yelps]
-[protestors screaming]
-[guinea pigs squealing]
[Marmalade grunts]
[all gasp]
It's not what it looks like.
[alarm blaring]
[Diane] "Trespassing,
burglary, mayhem,
assault with a deadly reptile"?
As if those poor rodents
haven't been through enough already!
No, Diane. Please.
Whoo! Okay. I'm sorry, Professor,
but I'm calling the chief.
-Please. Come on.
-[Diane] This experiment is over.
-[Marmalade] Experiments take time.
-You couldn't help yourself?
So I had a moment of weakness.
Sue me.
That's gonna be difficult
to do from prison!
Guys! What do we do now?
Hmph.
Time to launch a charm offensive.
Oh, yeah. The full Clooney.
Madam Governor. Diane.
Do not Clooney me, Wolf.
I see what's going on.
You think I'm still a bad guy
tryin' to bamboozle my way
to freedom.
But we've changed.
That flower of goodness
is blossoming all over the place.
[sighs]
Don't you ever get tired of lying?
No.
I mean…
Fudge.
That was a trick question, right?
[sighs]
I gave you an opportunity.
A chance to show the world
that you're more
than just a scary stereotype,
but you're too proud or too gutless
to take advantage of it.
Gutless? I'm gutless?
Oh-ho-ho!
I'm sorry, have we met?
I'm the villain of every story.
Guilty until proven innocent.
Even if by some miracle
we did change,
who's gonna believe us, huh?
Of course you wouldn't know
anything about that
with your Little-Miss-Perfect
power suits.
Is that so?
Wait a second, what did…
How did you…
A wolf and a fox
are not so different.
Maybe they will believe you,
maybe they won't.
But it doesn't matter.
Don't do it for them.
Do it for you.
This is a chance
to write your own story,
to find a better life for you
and your friends.
Come on,
what have you got to lose?
I don't know. My dignity?
Yeah, well,
that ship has already sailed.
[car door opens]
Believe it or not,
I'm rootin' for you, Wolf.
So you're not gonna call the chief?
I'll see you at the gala.
[cat meowing]
[meows]
I think we got off
to a bad start.
The name's Wolf.
[shrieks]
Yep. [sighs]
I get that a lot,
first impressions and all.
-[agitated meowing]
-No, no, no!
[yowling]
[panting]
It's okay, it's okay.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I know you're scared.
I would be, too, if I were you.
Just give me a chance.
Truth is,
we actually have a lot in common.
Don't tell anyone,
but I love a little scratch
on the spot behind my ears.
You know, right there.
The best.
Come on, kitty.
[sniffing]
[purring]
[purring continues]
Yeah. Who's a good kitty?
-Who's a good kitty?
-[Tarantula] Uh, Wolf?
Um, you saved him?
[Marmalade] Yes!
Yes, it's working.
You filmed that?
Yes, and they're starting
to like you.
-Yes!
-All right!
This might just be enough
to win over the guests at the gala.
-Now we're talking!
-All right!
[Tarantula]
Yeah, we did it! All right!
[Marmalade] Uh, Wolf?
I must say,
you've really turned a corner.
-You're really getting it.
-[Wolf] Really?
Oh, thanks.
No, I mean it.
I can see it from tip to tail.
It's just a shame that
you have to carry all that baggage.
What are you talk…
You mean the guys?
[Wolf] What do you mean?
[Marmalade]
You have great potential, Wolf.
But at some point,
you're going to have to choose
between your friends
or the good life.
[Shark, Piranha snoring]
Hey. You still awake?
[cat meowing]
You… You brought the cat in?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm just savin' it up for later.
Why, what's up?
I was just gettin' a little worried
since you've kinda become a…
Become a what?
You know, teacher's pet.
Gettin' all cozy with Marmalade.
Your tail waggin' and everything.
Well, yeah,
because it has to be believable.
Uh-huh. Yeah, I guess so.
As long as it's all part of the plan.
It is all part of the plan, isn't it?
Snake, buddy,
who made the plan to begin with?
You did.
So I'm the one who sticks to the plan
the most, right?
Yeah, all right. Yeah, okay.
I guess that makes sense, yeah.
But if the plan were ever to change,
you'd tell me, right?
You have my word.
Go bad…
Or go home.
Hey, Snake.
[Snake] Yeah?
You ever wonder what it'd be like?
The world loving us
instead of being scared of us?
You ever… You ever think about that?
[Snake] Loving us?
[laughs] Yeah, right.
I don't waste time thinkin' about
stuff that's never gonna happen.
[sighs] I can't wait for things
to get back to normal.
Yeah. Back to normal, back to normal.
What up!
We are just moments away
from Professor Marmalade's
Gala for Goodness,
where the legendary
Love Crater Meteorite
will be on display
for the first time ever.
But what everyone is really buzzing
about is the Bad Guys
whose heart-melting rescue video
has made them
an overnight viral sensation.
All right, guys, this is the big one.
The Golden Dolphin
is inside a titanium case
controlled by a randomly generated
five-digit code--
a code kept safe and secure
inside a briefcase
handcuffed to the chief of police.
[Piranha] She's not messin' around.
[Wolf] The code is only accessible
with her authorized fingerprints.
[Snake] Leave that to me.
[Wolf] While Snake gets the code,
Shark will secure the fake Dolphin.
[Shark] I like the sound of that.
[Wolf] Meanwhile, the rest of us
plant circuit jammers.
[Tarantula] Allowing me
to hack into the power grid.
[Wolf] At the end of the night,
we toast the professor…
Blah-blah-blah, yada yada…
and when I say "Marmalade,"
the lights go out,
and we'll have exactly four seconds
to make our move.
[Snake] The old switcheroo.
[Wolf] Chief hands Marmalade
the fake Dolphin.
We get our pardon.
Applause, applause, exit stage right,
and by the time
they realize what happened…
So long, suckers!
…we'll be drivin' off
into the sunset, legacy cemented.
-[all laugh]
-[Tarantula] Nice.
Gotta hand it to ya, buddy.
You're a real artist.
Well, Good Guys, this is it.
Good luck out there.
Remember, all eyes will be
on you tonight, not me.
Friends, meet the Good Guys!
[guests cheering]
Uh, this is different.
-Is this a prank?
-What's that sound?
Like screamin', but not terrified.
All right, guys.
Let's, uh-- Let's mingle.
It's crime time, baby.
♪ Fly me to the moon
And let me play among the stars ♪
There you go.
♪ Let me see what spring is like
On Jupiter and Mars ♪
Okay, fake Dolphin,
fake Dolphin, fake Dolphin.
Bingo.
Mr. Shark! Mr. Shark!
Is it true sharks can smell blood
a mile away?
What? No. That's freaky.
[laughing]
Mr. Wolf! Mr. Wolf!
-Whoa!
-It is a pleasure to meet you.
Pleasure is all mine.
I loved your video.
Can I get a picture for my kids?
Hey, just a minute, guys. Let me…
I gotta… I'll be right back.
Okay, Wolf, what are you up to?
With criminals like this,
you gotta be crafty,
subtle, invisible.
And then,
the moment they let their guard down…
-Whammo!
-[muffled shouting]
You spring the trap!
Always one step ahead.
I think I've earned a tonic water.
Put it in a fun glass, huh?
Oh! Nice.
-[Snake choking]
-[gasps]
-Oh, no.
-[yelps]
[stammering]
[Wolf grunting]
-[chuckles]
-Hey.
-That's right, be intimidated.
-[Snake groaning]
[both] No, no, no!
♪ Look at me ♪
[guests murmuring]
-What?
-Hmm?
Mmm.
♪ Tell me what you see ♪
♪ Am I good or bad? ♪
♪ Don't you judge so fast ♪
[guests cheering]
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ I know you think you know me
You made your own conclusion ♪
♪ You think that I look scary
Well, that's your own delusion ♪
♪ Listen when I tell you
There's more than meets the eye ♪
♪ So take a closer look
To find a real good guy ♪
♪ We're not the bad guys ♪
[Diane] Mr. Wolf.
Diane…
Yeah, what a surprise.
You know, if I didn't know better,
I'd think that you were avoiding me.
Avoiding you?
Why would I do that?
Okay.
But I have to say,
I'm a little disappointed.
I was hoping
you were gonna ask me to dance.
Oh.
♪ Get up on the floor ♪
♪ We're gonna be good tonight
Wanna get you feeling right ♪
We're the good, good guys ♪
♪ We're gonna be good tonight
Wanna get you feeling right ♪
We're the good, good guys ♪
♪ Come on! ♪
-Whoo-ooh!
-I see.
You lost the sheep's clothing.
Yeah. Figured it was time
I got comfortable in my own fur.
♪ If you're feelin' good in here ♪
♪ I said
If you're feelin' good in here ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
I think I like the new you.
Well, that makes two of us.
♪ We're all here to have
A good, good time ♪
♪ Let the rhythm move you
And open up your mind ♪
♪ Next time you see me
In your neighborhood ♪
♪ Don't you be thinkin' that
I'm up to no good ♪
♪ I just want you
To give me a chance ♪
♪ I know your body really wants
To dance… ♪
Break out the umbrellas,
because it's raining money!
All because of…
I can't even believe I'm saying this…
All because of the Bad Guys!
♪ I wanna get you feeling right
We're gonna be good tonight ♪
♪ We're the good, good guys ♪
♪ We're gonna be good tonight ♪
♪ Wanna get you feeling right
We're gonna be good tonight ♪
♪ We're the good, good guys ♪
So, how does it feel
to have everyone not fear you
for a change?
[muffled cheering]
It feels… good.
Real good.
Diane…
[Diane gasps]
It belongs to you.
♪ Go to it, two, three ♪
♪ We're the good, good guys
We're gonna be good tonight ♪
♪ Wanna get you feeling right
♪ We're the good, good guys ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
[guests cheering, applauding]
Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Wolf.
As you know, the money raised tonight
will be delivered tomorrow
to schools, hospitals and other
worthy causes across the city!
[Wolf clears throat]
I just wanna take a moment
to recognize
the one responsible
for our new outlook.
Our brilliant mentor…
-Do it.
-Come on.
The one and only, Professor…
-[Tarantula] Wolf! Do it.
-Professor…
Um…
Professor Marmalade!
[guests cheering]
Chief, may I do the honors?
That's not the plan.
What is happening?
He's gone rogue.
A deal's a deal.
By the power vested in me,
it is a pleasure to
grant the Bad Guys a full par…
[guests gasping, murmuring]
That was weird.
The meteorite is gone!
[guest] Somebody stole it!
-[Chief grunts]
-Chief.
Wolf.
Come on, you can't possibly think
that we did this.
So long, suckers!
Run!
Get them!
Uh…
[nervous chuckle]
Here, here.
-What are you doing?
-I'm giving it all back.
Huh?
[Wolf] Excuse me.
What happened back there?
-I couldn't do it.
-What do you mean you couldn't do it?
-[Wolf] I just…
-No!
I do not run.
That is not how I roll.
Piranha, don't do anything crazy.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
"Crazy" is what I bring
to the party, chico.
[Shark groans]
You're makin' a mistake.
We didn't do it.
I know we always say that,
but this time it's actually true.
La, la, la, la, la. Can't hear you.
-Guilty, guilty, guilty!
-Talk to Marmalade.
We're really good now.
He'll tell you.
Professor…
Tonight's headline:
Change is Impossible.
You should always judge a book
by its cover,
and all stereotypes
have been affirmed.
Stop, for goodness' sake!
Let me speak to them.
I'm sure there's been
some misunderstanding.
[door opens]
[sighs] Professor Marmalade.
You've got five minutes.
No deals this time.
You have to help us. Tell them.
Tell them we didn't do it.
There, there. Of course
you didn't do it. How could you?
After all, you're such a good boy.
You're such a good boy.
That shiver up my spine.
The wag in my tiny tail.
Arrest them!
What if we tried
a little experiment, Diane?
As you know,
my Gala for Goodness…
[Tiffany Fluffit] Where the legendary
Love Crater Meteorite
will be on display
for the first time ever.
All eyes will be on you tonight,
not me.
You're such a…
[low voice] Good boy.
You.
It was all you.
What are you talkin' about, Wolf?
The old lady, the Golden Dolphin,
good training…
It was all to get us here
so he could steal the meteorite
and let us take the fall.
Whoa, what old lady?
And why would a guinea pig
want a meteorite anyway?
[Marmalade cackling]
Uh, guys? He's creepin' me out.
Wait, what?
What's goin' on?
Someone turn me around.
Well, well. So, you finally get it.
[all] What?
You stole the meteorite?
It's not just a meteorite.
I told you guys it's a butt.
It's not a butt!
[exhales]
It's the ultimate power source.
You see, when it struck,
scientists found that it emitted
an electromagnetic frequency
unlike anything else on earth.
I'm going to harness its power
to pull off the greatest heist
the world has ever seen.
You should've eaten him
when you had the chance.
-Yep.
-But why us?
Because you're the perfect patsies.
Come on, when people look up "bad"
in the dictionary,
do they see a sweet,
adorable guinea pig?
No. They see you.
And they always will.
Okay. Fine.
But you set us up.
Oh, pish-pish.
Let's be honest.
Evolution set you up.
But Wolfie here really clinched it.
You fell for every one of my traps,
starting with saving
a helpless little old lady.
Wolf. What's he talkin' about?
[Marmalade] Whoops.
Did I say too much?
Anyhoo, looks like yet again
the big, bad wolf got outsmarted
by a little piggy.
[growls]
You little pouchy-cheeked rat!
I'll kill you, you hear me?
-[Marmalade] Help! Help!
-You're dead! You're dead…
Help!
The big, bad wolf is attacking me.
Now you are done forever, Wolf!
[sirens wailing]
[Marmalade shuddering]
Professor, Professor,
any thoughts on how the Bad Guys
managed to steal the meteorite
in plain sight?
Well, off the top of my head,
perhaps they accessed
the site previously
and set up an intricate system
of tunnels and trapdoors
that could be remotely triggered
to suck the meteorite
down into a holding area.
-But how should I know?
-[Tiffany Fluffit] Totally.
[Marmalade] I mean, they're
the deranged masterminds. Not me.
[Wolf] I'm giving it all back.
I can't believe we got double-crossed
by a tiny rodent.
Oh, we got double-crossed
by a rodent, all right.
But, uh, not a tiny one.
What?
This was supposed to be
us conning Marmalade.
It turns out, it was Wolf conning us.
[gagging]
Does that sound familiar
to you, Wolf?
Why would you think that?
I don't know,
maybe because you just sabotaged
the biggest heist of our lives?
I think you owe us
an explanation, buddy.
[sighs]
Okay. You're right.
This is what happened.
Back in the museum, I just tried
to steal an old lady's purse.
Classic snatch and grab.
"Tried to"?
Since when do you try to steal
something and not just steal it?
I was trying to steal the purse,
when the old lady fell…
[clears throat]
…and I kinda helped her.
What?
I kinda helped her.
But then you stole her purse?
No. I didn't.
I saved the old lady,
and she hugged me,
and my tail wagged,
and I didn't know what it was,
but it felt, you know…
good.
[all gasp]
Ah! But then,
you stole the purse?
[all] No!
You know, I heard what the pig said
to you about cuttin' us loose.
Wait. Like, "us" us?
But I never thought
you'd actually do it, man.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I would never… I was tryin' to…
I was trying to find us
a better life.
Our life was perfect
until you decided to ruin it.
[Wolf] I didn't.
You guys felt it at the gala.
The clapping, the cheering.
We were more than
just scary villains. They loved us.
Oh, yeah? If they loved us so much,
how come we're in prison
for a crime we didn't commit?
You know what?
I'll give Marmalade this:
At least he sees the world
for what it is:
A place where some people are scary
and some people are scared.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I'm tired of bein' scary.
I'm tired of bein' an outcast.
-Maybe I don't wanna be a--
-What? A bad guy?
Don't wanna be
a bad guy anymore, huh?
Say it, Wolf!
Yeah, I thought so.
And us? Your lifelong friends?
We're just holdin' you back?
Yeah, maybe you are!
[gasps]
-Take it back.
-Snake!
Take it back! Apologize!
Hey, hey, hey!
Prison is no place for fighting.
Tell that to him.
[Wolf] Huh?
-What?
-[shouting]
[grunts, shouts]
[shouts]
[high-pitched shout, screams]
-[guard screaming]
-Shh.
[shouts]
[screams]
[both grunt]
Wait, wait! Hold…
[all gasp] Diane?
But how do you know how to do
all of that kick-kick-punch-punch?
Wait a sec, you're the Crimson Paw?
[Wolf] The Queen of Cons,
Acrobatic Swiss Army Knife,
stole the Zumpango diamond twice,
once for profit,
second time just for fun.
Never identified, never caught.
[chuckles] Guess I'm still the best
bad guy the world has ever seen.
-[sighs] At least I used to be.
-[alarm blaring]
-[guards screaming]
-[Wolf, Shark gasp]
[screams]
Nope, I am still the best.
Just like riding a stolen bicycle.
Oh. Uh, you got a little… Ouch.
Hey, why…
Why did you save us anyway?
After the gala,
I knew something wasn't right.
So, I did some investigating,
and that meteor…
I know.
Some kinda
cosmic-mega-super-antennae thing.
Right. If conducted through
an array of ionized crystals,
it will generate
a massive psychokinetic field
the size of a city.
Oh, my gosh, did I interrupt you?
Were you gonna say that?
Uh… I was gonna be
a little more technical,
-but you got the gist of it.
-[Diane laughs]
Marmalade needs to be stopped,
but I can't do it alone.
You know his compound
better than anyone.
You can count on us.
Right, guys?
There is no "us."
We're through, Wolf.
Done. Finito.
Because of
that little tiff back there?
Come on, man, that's what we do.
You serve, I volley.
That's our little dance.
Not this time.
Piranha?
Webs?
Sorry, Wolfie.
Shark…
Hmm.
Hey.
Guys?
You wanna know
why I hate birthdays, Wolf?
Do you?
When you grow up a snake,
nobody shows up to your party.
Birthdays are a constant reminder
that out there
I'm just a scary,
good-for-nothin' monster.
Yeah.
But nothing compares
to havin' the one guy--
the one guy I thought I could trust--
stab me in the back.
Come on, guys. Let's get outta here.
[helicopter approaching]
[electricity crackling]
Now, this is what a true bad guy
looks like.
[helmet whirs]
What do you say we have some fun?
[maniacal laughing]
[laughing continues]
[screeching]
[gasping]
[people screaming]
Hey.
You okay?
No, I'm not okay.
I'm very, very un-okay.
Um, I just left the only friends
I have ever had, so what am…
What am I doin'?
[sighs]
I know this isn't easy,
leaving everything behind.
-Do you?
-Yeah.
I was the best thief in the world.
Fast, fearless, inventive.
I just had one thing left to steal.
The Golden Dolphin.
So you went after it.
I didn't just go after it.
I had it.
And a clear escape route.
But…
all I saw in the end
was the tricky fox
that they always told me I was.
It changed everything.
So, now, instead of hurting people,
I'm helping them.
I'm still me. [chuckles]
I'm just me, on the right side.
You're doing the right thing.
And some day, your friends,
if they're real friends,
I think they'll understand.
Now, come on, let's get inside.
You look like
you just busted out of a prison.
[chuckling]
-[thuds]
-[both gasp]
[guinea pig chittering]
Guinea pigs?
-[gasps]
-[both] Marmalade!
Let's bounce.
So, this is the hideout
of the great Crimson Paw.
-[Diane chuckles]
-[keypad beeping]
Snack break?
Okay, oddly timed, but you do you.
-[automated voice] Identity verified.
-What?
Welcome, Diane.
Whoa!
Holy moly!
Ah! It's so good to be home.
Are you kiddin' me?
Laser-sighted zip line?
The XM 2400 Radar Jammer? No way!
I actually prefer the earlier model.
Agree to disagree.
This stuff is nice too. [screams]
Yeah, that's a blowtorch.
Also, not really your color.
Ugh.
[Diane] All righty.
Marmalade, what are you up to,
you fuzzy little weirdo?
We need eyes on the city.
Let's see if we can't hack into the
government's surveillance satellite.
But you're the governor.
Couldn't you just ask?
Yeah, but the paperwork.
[beeping]
[Diane mumbling]
I am definitely picking up on
suspicious activity here.
Those are guinea pig heat signatures.
Marmalade seems to be
controlling them.
But to do what?
There are no obvious targets.
That's because
they're moving targets.
[gasps] His charity fundraiser.
He's gonna steal the money.
Raised in his own name?
It's the greatest heist
the world's ever seen.
One billion dollars inside trucks
on their way to charities
all over the city.
We need to cut off
Marmalade's communication
with his guinea pig army.
If there's no signal…
There's no heist.
[both]
We have to steal the meteorite.
That was very cute…
-All right.
-…what we just did there.
Put on your big-girl pants.
We're gearin' up.
I wouldn't take that. Those things
rip your pants right off.
Huh. Try wearing clean underwear.
Just in case.
What…
You stole my car?
Respect.
Let's do this.
-[elevator bell dings]
-[all gasp]
-[Shark] No!
-[Snake] What?
[Piranha] All our stuff?
-[Tarantula] Oh, no.
-Where is everything?
-No, no, no!
-All our stuff.
-It's all gone!
-My disguise closet!
[Tarantula]
Where's my things?
Wolf gave away all our loot!
We stole it fair and square!
Now I understand what it feels like
to have things stolen from you.
[panting] I don't like it.
I really don't like it! [whimpering]
-[grumbles]
-[Shark crying] We got no food.
We got no money. We got no money
we could use to buy food.
No food we can sell for money.
We… [cries]
All right! Okay, okay.
Here, here. Take it.
Now, stop cryin', buddy.
Oh!
Um… Snake, what did you just do?
What? My friend was sad.
I was just cheerin' him up.
You…
You did a good thing. For me.
Don't be ridiculous.
I just put your needs before my own.
-Yeah. You're being good.
-I'm not.
I was simply making a sacrifice
so Shark could be happy.
That is the actual definition
of being good.
Snake!
You! The worst one of us!
-The most selfish.
-Spiteful.
-Terrible.
-Sneaky.
-Dishonest.
-Insensitive.
-Manipulative.
-Snake-like.
-Stanky.
-And your point is?
I think Wolf was right.
Maybe we could be
more than just scary villains.
[gasps]
What…
[Tarantula] Oh, wow!
Is this… Is this "wagging"?
[Tarantula] We're wagging!
No! No! No!
We'll always be bad guys!
[panting]
[cackling]
Faster, faster, my little pigs.
[children cheering]
-[thudding]
-[tires screeching]
[all gasping]
[chitters]
[screams]
No!
[cackling]
[driver screams]
[all screaming]
[chittering]
[people screaming]
[tires screeching]
Once we steal the meteorite,
we take it straight to the police.
And all will be forgiven.
I don't know about "all,"
but it's a start.
That's strange.
Why would Marmalade
leave the Golden Dolphin unprotected?
Because maybe it's a trap.
-Or maybe…
-Wait, wait, wait!
[Wolf screaming]
Yeah, it was a trap.
[Marmalade] Well, well, well.
If it isn't my prized pupil.
And you've brought along
the governor.
Or should I say, the Crimson Paw?
[gasps, grunts]
What an ingenious way
to disguise the Zumpango diamond.
Hiding it in plain sight.
You gotta be kidding me.
What? I'm sentimental.
You always did have panache.
And yet,
you still fell right into my trap.
But how did you know
we'd even be here?
Oh, I got a little tip…
from a friend.
[Snake hissing]
Hey, buddy. How's it hangin'?
Snake.
[laughs]
What can I say? We just clicked.
Oh, yeah? How's it feel to be workin'
for your favorite food?
Ah, you're just jealous
to be missin' out
on the heist of the century.
It's got everything.
Betrayal, a meteor, mind control.
Can I try it on?
-Of course, partner.
-Nice.
All the crime
with none of the exercise.
And what about all that
"Flower of goodness" talk?
Was it all just a lie?
Uh, pretty much, yeah.
You see,
I never cared about what's "good."
Only what's good for me.
Like, say, a billion dollars.
Ooh! I just got a tingle.
[laughing]
[Marmalade, Snake laughing]
Go bad…
Or go home.
Cuddles! Finish them.
[both screaming]
[Wolf grunting]
[screams] Poison gas?
Don't breathe it in.
Wait a second. [sniffs]
That's not poison gas.
-[Piranha] Sorry!
-[Wolf gasps]
[Shark, Tarantula gasping]
Surprise! [laughing]
[Wolf] What?
-Guys! I can't believe it's you.
-You were right, Wolfie.
-We felt the wag, man.
-[Piranha] And the tingle.
-It's good, right?
-[Shark] Oh, yeah!
This is super moving,
but can we do this later?
Feels like I got
a rhythm section in my fin!
[beatboxing]
[Diane] Come on!
Spinning blades!
Oh, yeah. Right.
Sorry. I got it.
Guys,
am I happy to see you!
-[Wolf sighs]
-[Piranha chuckles]
Now it's time to huff and puff and
blow this little piggy's heist down.
-[Tarantula] Game over, guinea pig!
-[all cheering]
With this meteorite,
we will be able to commit crimes
people have only dreamed about.
Not bad for a butt rock.
Once again, it's not a…
-[gasps]
-Don't mind us,
just robbin' this place.
No, no, no!
-Here, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
-[cat meows]
[Wolf] Whoo-hoo!
-[Shark] Yeah!
-[Tarantula] All right!
We did it!
Now, to get this thing to the chief
and clear your names.
Weird. Usually,
we drive away from the police.
Hey, chico, are you sure
we stopped the heist?
-Yeah.
-Relax.
Marmalade can't control them
if he doesn't have the meteorite.
So, who's drivin' those trucks?
-[chittering]
-[Diane] The meteorite!
-It's still transmitting.
-Uh-oh.
The charity money.
Change of plan, guys.
Webs, is there some way to override
the truck's navigation system?
We'd need some kind of
magnetized cross-circuit interceptor.
You mean this?
Ooh! She just keeps gettin' cooler!
Oh, yeah!
[Wolf] Whoo!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh, no.
We gotta split up.
Webs, you feel like a girls' trip?
Um, yes.
[Tarantula] Later, boys. [laughs]
["Go" playing]
♪ Everything gettin' harder to find ♪
♪ Everybody jumpin'
Out of they mind ♪
I wanna go on the girls' trip.
♪ But that's where we begin
You feel it ♪
♪ Mannequins say
"We breakin' the mold" ♪
♪ Breakin' out
And we breakin' the codes ♪
♪ Similar to the Jacques Cousteau
To the depths and you're wet ♪
♪ So your tank explodes
So get it out ♪
Whoo-hoo!
♪ Everybody got a target tonight ♪
♪ Everybody come along for the ride ♪
♪ All you studs and you duds
And your ladies, let's fly ♪
-You're insured, right?
-Yeah, why?
[grunts]
[Wolf] That's… Hey!
That's my car!
It's ceviche, baby! [cackles]
♪ No time to rest ♪
♪ Just do your best ♪
♪ What you hear is not a test ♪
♪ We're only here to make you ♪
♪ We're only here to make you go! ♪
♪ Go! ♪
[laughs]
So long, suckers.
♪ Go! ♪
Whoop-bam!
[screeching]
♪ Go! ♪
-Whoo-hoo!
-Yeah!
Where'd you learn to do that?
Well, I'm, you know,
kind of a natural.
Mostly YouTube.
-Nice work.
-Meet me at the police station.
Don't be late.
What do you say we deliver
this butt rock to the chief?
♪ Just do your best ♪
♪ What you hear is not a test ♪
[squealing]
[Marmalade] No, no, no!
That's my stolen money!
What good are you if you can't even
anticipate their next move?
-Oh, so, it's my fault?
-Yeah.
♪ We're only here to make you
We're only here to make you ♪
♪ Go! ♪
-Chief.
-This better be good.
Trust me.
You don't wanna miss this.
[gasps] Look!
[tires squealing]
Well, butter my crumpets.
Can it be? The Bad Guys
are returning the meteorite?
Perhaps this is the feel-good story
we all need.
-Whoo-hoo!
-Yeah!
Do you guys think
they'll throw us a party?
Yeah. With fireworks,
piñatas and cake.
[tires screeching]
[Wolf sighs]
We can't do this without him.
He might be a Mr. Grumpypants.
But he's our Mr. Grumpypants.
[Piranha] Yeah.
Wolf!
I'm starting to see why
your friends dumped you.
I don't have any friends!
-[horn honking]
-[Wolf] Snake! Snake!
Wolf?
Snake, come back!
We need you, baby!
[Tarantula] And you need us!
Oh, there you go again,
making it personal.
I'll give you one last chance
to give me the meteorite.
Oh, yeah?
What you gonna do, Whiskers?
-This.
-[helmet whirs]
[Shark gasps]
What the…
[chittering]
-We've got adorable company.
-Floor it!
[Wolf] Whoa!
Maybe I shouldn't have called him
"Whiskers."
[gasping]
When I woke up this morning,
this is not where
I saw the day going.
Whoa!
[Wolf] Come on!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, hey,
let's dial this down a notch, huh?
Besides, you'll never get him.
He's too good a driver.
Hmm. You're right.
But now that I think of it,
maybe it would be better to exploit
his greatest weakness.
Exactly.
Wait.
No!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
-Hold on, hold it, hold it, hold it.
-[laughing]
Okay, okay. You win.
You can have the space rock.
Good boy, Wolf.
[helmet whirs]
[Wolf] Take the wheel.
Not so fast! Pull him up first.
Or I'll use this.
Oh, come, now.
[Snake laughing]
Do it, or you'll lose the rock.
If you insist. Cuddles!
You want him?
He's yours.
[screams]
[screaming continues]
Snake!
-No, no, no!
-Snake!
Oh, no!
[Snake screaming]
Guys, I know it's crazy,
but we're gonna jump it.
Crazy? You finally speaking
my language, chico!
We're gonna make it!
[Piranha screaming]
You came back.
[Wolf grunting]
Snake,
I should've been honest with you.
I was afraid that if you knew
I wanted to be good, that you'd…
Act like a jerk
and never talk to you again?
[laughing] Yeah.
Point is, I… [stammers]
Yeah. I love you too, buddy.
This… This is so beautiful.
Do you know how beautiful this is,
you guys? [crying]
Now…
Now you gonna make me cry.
I know.
So pathetic, right?
Come on, guys.
Who said it was the end?
-[all gasp]
-[Snake laughs]
-[Piranha] Whoo-hoo!
-[Snake laughing]
Gah!
[Marmalade] No! Cuddles!
We're losing altitude!
We're going down!
[gasps, coughs]
What happened?
Did we blow up?
Is this heaven?
[Wolf grunting]
[officers chattering]
-[laughs] That is it.
-[Piranha] Hey!
There is absolutely no way
you're getting away this time.
Wait, Chief.
Governor Foxington?
-Don't do this.
-[Wolf] Ow!
They didn't steal the meteorite.
They were bringing it back.
Ha! How could you know that?
Unless…
Unless you were conspiring
with a bunch of known criminals.
Well… [clears throat]
…as a matter of fact,
it's time I came clean
about something.
The truth is I'm really…
[clears throat]
-…really--
-Really a big fan of redemption arcs.
Yeah, we know.
-We're done runnin' away.
-Yeah.
-Yep.
Chief, do what you need to do.
What?
Y-- You're turning yourself in?
We might not have
stolen the meteorite,
but we did steal
a lot of other things.
It's time we took
some responsibility.
Start a clean state.
Take us in, Chief.
Wow, really?
You finally did it.
This is your moment, Chief.
Drink it in.
[gasps] Wow!
You know, I should give a speech.
Well, I should, shouldn't I?
-Uh…
-[Chief clears throat]
When I was six years old,
I decided that
I wanted to play the piccolo,
only to find that my fingers
were just too powerful
for that fragile little instrument.
And that's when I discovered
law enforcement.
[chuckles]
I'm proud of you, Wolf.
You know, a fox and a wolf
are not that different.
You got a good thing
goin' here, Governor.
So, it turns out the saga
of the Bad Guys has come to
a simple and totally satisfying
conclusion.
Though, I wonder,
what happened to the meteorite?
[Marmalade] Cuddles! Faster, faster!
[Tiffany Fluffit]
It's Professor Marmalade!
He's bringing the meteorite back!
Huh?
Uh, yes. Yes.
Bringing it back.
That's precisely what I am doing.
Look no further.
Your hero has arrived.
Professor, care to comment?
I tried to help them, Tiffany.
But in the end,
it's the same old story.
Bad guys, bad.
Good guys, good.
So true. So wise.
Furthermore,
for the good of the city,
I have generously decided
to take the meteorite back
to my compound for safekeeping.
[crowd cheering]
Is he seriously
gonna get away with this?
Thank you.
Gosh, you're kind.
Give it up for me!
[Chief] Wait a second.
This isn't the meteorite!
-It's a lamp!
-[Marmalade gasps]
-[all] Huh?
-[laughing]
[all] What?
[Tarantula]
Snake, what did you just do?
[Snake] What? My friend was sad,
and I was just cheerin' him up.
[Tarantula] I think Wolf was right.
Maybe we could be
more than just scary villains.
I'm bad, you're bad.
Let's be bad together.
You've got yourself a deal.
-Can I try it on?
-Of course, partner.
-[Snake gasps]
-Don't mind us,
just robbin' this place.
No, no, no!
-But if that's a lamp, where is the…
-[Snake laughing]
The old switcheroo.
[clicks]
[police radio chatter]
[engine starts]
[purring]
[siren wailing]
It's a butt.
[whistling]
Hold on.
This is the Zumpango diamond!
But this was stolen by the…
[gasps]
By the Crimson Paw!
-Me? No, no, no.
-[crowd murmuring]
OMG.
-And a shocking twist.
-You're making a huge mistake.
The notorious bandit
known as the Crimson Paw
has been revealed to be
none other than Professor Marmalade.
[Marmalade] I'm not the Crimson Paw.
She's the Crimson Paw.
She's the Paw!
I'm a flower of goodness! No!
Whoo! That's my reptile, right there.
-That's what I'm talkin' about.
-Yeah!
Come on, somebody had to
destroy that meteorite.
That thing was dangerous.
That was pretty good there, Snakey.
Good? It was genius.
Not only did I foil the pig,
I got you to admit
how much you care about me.
Sure, yeah.
I just wonder about one little thing.
Oh, yeah? What's that, Wolf?
Who do you think
put that one Push Pop in the fridge?
Wait.
You…
-No.
-I knew you were good.
No!
We good, baby.
-We good.
-Yeah!
♪ Feeling all right ♪
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ I'm not feeling too good myself ♪
♪ Yeah, you're feelin' all right ♪
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ I'm not feeling too good
Little girl ♪
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ Seems I've got to have
A change of scene ♪
♪ Every night I have ♪
♪ The strangest dreams ♪
♪ Imprisoned by the way
It could have been ♪
♪ Left here on my own
Or so it seems ♪
[Wolf] Okay.
So, imagine it's your birthday.
-[Snake] It is my birthday.
-[Wolf] Yeah, I know.
But we're walkin' along,
and you meet a genie.
-[Snake] Okay. What's his name?
-What's the genie's name?
Yeah, I wanna know
who I'm talkin' to.
I don't know.
"Genie," or "Gene" for short.
So he offers you three wishes.
Why three?
You know, industry standard.
Now, what do you wish for?
-Uh…
-Good luck out there, guys.
I'm gonna go with nothin'.
Nothing?
Come on, it's your birthday.
All right!
But what do I need wishes for?
I got my freedom.
-Hey.
-Guys!
Lookin' good, hermanos!
-I got my friends.
-Aw.
I've got the skin
of a reptile half my age.
I don't know about "half your age,"
but you look good.
Well,
that's because you just molted.
Yes, I did.
You smell good, too.
I'm shiny, I'm gorgeous.
[all laughing]
[Wolf] Huh.
[Tarantula] Um…
So, what do we do now?
-[Piranha] Steal a car?
-[Wolf] Piranha!
I was joking.
It was a joke!
You know, on second thought, Wolf,
maybe I'd wish for a ride.
[Wolf] Oh, yeah? Alakazam.
Nice.
Hey, guys.
Ready to get to work?
[meows]
Hey! Whoa!
[engine revs]
Hey, you.
That's right, come here.
A little closer.
I said, "Closer."
Now that we've had some time
to get acquainted, uh,
not so scary now, are we?
Webs, hit it.
["Brand New Day" playing]
[all laughing]
[Piranha] Whoo-hoo!
♪ Well, I'm so excited ♪
♪ There's no disguising ♪
♪ I'm on a road
To a brand-new horizon ♪
♪ The time is right
To change this life ♪
♪ Give me the sunshine ♪
♪ Bring me the light
So I can see it ♪
♪ Believin' I'm gonna seize it ♪
♪ It's a brand-new day ♪
♪ And I can see it ♪
♪ Believin' I'm gonna seize it ♪
♪ It's a brand-new, brand-new day ♪
♪ A brand-new day ♪
♪ For my brand-new ways ♪
♪ Somebody tell me
Are you ready for change? ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ I know our new, different path
Seems strange ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ When the hunch is calling
Don't waste your time ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Carpe diem and go blow your mind ♪
♪ I see the light
And I'm coming to get you ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ You gotta thank the Lord though
Gotta paint the picture ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ I'm the same same
With a different mind ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ This new life
Got me feeling right ♪
♪ 'Cause I can see it ♪
♪ Believin' I'm gonna seize it ♪
♪ It's a brand-new day ♪
♪ And I can see it ♪
♪ Believin' I'm gonna seize it ♪
♪ It's a brand-new, brand-new day ♪
♪ A brand-new day ♪
[all laughing]
-[Piranha] Whoo!
-[laughing continues]